Md Saidul Islam Khan | BBA (Management)

House No.:11(Ground Floor), Road No.:15, Sector-12,

Uttara Model Town, Dhaka-1230 E-mail: saidul.khan@gmail.com

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/md-saidul-islam-khan-647436107/

Mobile: +880 1717902033 | +880 1676377455

Skype: saidul90

SUMMERY:

Executed domestic and global sourcing activities for electronics home appliances manufacturing projects, machineries and automobiles. Implemented new procurement policy for the company which cuts down the production cost by 10% and maintenance cost up to 40%.

- Experienced in procurement & purchase both local and global market, Bank corresponding, Documentation, Costing and Tax calculation, Clearing and Freight forwarding, Logistics Support.
- Having experience to work with global market leaders like Gigabyte Technology Co. LTD., Toshiba, Philips LiteOn Digital Solutions Corp., Western Digital, Seagate, Clevo INC., Daimler AG, NTN (Japan), SKF (Sweden), Volvo Powertrain, Volvo Eicher Commercial Vehicles, Tata Motors, TATA Hitachi throughout the carrier path as stakeholder as well as local market leaders.
- Worked in supply chain management, process development, integrated business planning and operation, after sales service, sourcing, and forecasting.
- Proven multitasking with effective communication skills practiced as a planner and commercial individual.
- Highly organized, enthusiastic & self-starter to my team with a creative flair for team work.

WORK EXPERIENCE:

Asst. Manager (Acting In-charge), Procurement and Purchase Dept. Lal Teer Seed LTD.

Multimode Group, Dhaka, Bangladesh (March 2018- Currently working)

- Collect annual purchase and procurement requisition/demand from various departments/companies well in advance of beginning the following financial year.
- Preparing of Annual Purchase & Procurement Budget for the Group based on the Actual consumption during previous years and Company/ Dept. wise Annual purchase & procurement Requisition/Demand.
- Preparing of Activity Plan for implementing of the projected Budget under consultation and understanding with financial management for maintaining of payment schedule with the suppliers.
- Market analysis and collecting of various sources of supply for various types of procuring materials.
- Submitting of periodical purchase demand/proposal to the Procurement Committee seeking approval for tendering quotation for required supply and making comparative price analysis to procure at the competitive price under approval of management.
- Visit working site of supplier to ensure quality supply of materials within the time schedule.
- Interim reporting to management about work in progress about the ordered supply.
- Certification of bills against supply received and follow up with Fin & Accts to ensure timely payment.
- Standard MIS reporting to management.

Senior Executive, Sourcing and Procurement, Import Operations Department, Walton Corporation LTD.

Walton Group, Dhaka, Bangladesh. (February 2017 – February 2018)

- Learned how to manage all kinds commercial issues for import operations and Gained a vast knowledge about documentation, record keeping and tracking, NBR policies and procedures and got familiar with different SROs of NBR.
- Became acquainted in sourcing for new products and new suppliers for existing products and negotiating with suppliers for best deal.
- Set new suppliers with best deals which hits revenue upwards by 7%.
- Found out some local manufacturers for imported items which cut down the production cost almost



10%.

- Do the planning for product shipments according to the production requirements and market demand and synchronizing the inventory, production and import operations department.
- Reduced inventory by 10% by implementing intimate planning with Sales, Manufacturing and Procurement
- Become acquainted with the process of taking permission from CCI&E for export and re-import of goods (Servicing purpose).

Senior Executive, Sourcing and Commercial, Walton Hi-Tech Industries LTD.

Walton Group, Dhaka, Bangladesh. (November 2015 – January 2017)

- Discovered various sourcing and procure raw materials, machines and spare parts for production of consumer electronics like refrigerators, air conditioners, televisions and motorcycle etc.
- Established myself as a good negotiator with suppliers for better price and better lead time for delivery of purchased goods.
- Aggressively worked to achieve significant cost savings through sourcing new suppliers and negotiating with the existing ones and Earned better price, service and extended warranty from existing suppliers by re-negotiating with them which again effects on production cost down by 5% to 7%.
- Developed new suppliers for raw materials which reduced the production cost by 10%.
- Converted various locally procured (imported) items to direct import to ensure better quality and pricing that gradually leads up to 30% savings on procurement and brought an end to monopoly business of local importers.
- Responsible for all kinds of Automobile spare parts and vehicle procurement and reduced the fleet maintenance cost up to 40% by setting up new suppliers and source.
- Gathered knowledge about import operations, L/C procedures, Documentation, how to declare goods according to H.S. codes, Bangladesh Import policy, NBR regulations and trained about commercial procedures, INCO terms, Import via Bank, L/C procedures by the professionals
- Visited some world famous and locally renowned supplier's factories like DAIMLER AG, TATA, TATA HITACHI, MAN to ensure quality and authenticity and earned huge practical knowledge about production process and planning.
- Travelled China and India several times for new business development and attending different fairs like China Export-Import (Canton) fair for sourcing new suppliers.

EDUCATION HISTORY:

- Master of Business Administration (MBA) (June 2015 Currently Enrolled)
 Finance and Banking (27 Credit Completed),
 Jahangirnagar University (JU)
- Bachelor of Business Administration (BBA) (January 2009 November 2012)
 Management (CGPA 3.57 out of 4)
 Stamford University

VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCE:

• Member, Badhon (Blood Donating Organization)

TRAINING:

- 'Learning the Import Operation & H.S. Codes' by Walton.
- 'Secretes of Personal & Interpersonal Leaderships' by Walton.
- 'Logistics, Inventory and Store Management' By Dhaka Chamber of commerce and industry.

OTHER SKILLS:

- Computer Skills: **Microsoft Office** (Word, Excel, Office, Power Point, Outlook).
- Language Skills: **English Good in speaking and writing skills (IELTS Score:6.0),** Bengali Native Tongue.